asmallorange.com 2011-11-01

# Privacy Policy | A Small Orange Web Hosting

## Privacy Policy

* * *

Privacy is extremely important at A Small Orange and we are committed to ensuring that we respect and protect our customers' privacy. The three basic tenets of our privacy policies here at A Small Orange are:

  *  **Collect only what we need.** We will not ask you for information we do not need to serve you in some way. Our job is to be your web hosting company, not to be a data mining company.
  * **Share only when we have to.** We do not and will not share any of your personal information unless we have your permission or we are required to do so by law or similar process.
  * **Ensure that we keep private information private.** We will do what we can (within reason, of course) to ensure that any personal information you have given us will remains private.

The three tenets above are intentionally very simple. If you are interested in more details regarding our privacy policies, keep reading. If you have any questions, feel free to get [get in touch with us](mailto:help@asmallorange.com).

### A Small Orange LLC Privacy Policy

A Small Orange LLC ("A Small Orange") provides a variety of web hosting products and services to its international customer base. It is our policy to respect and protect our customers' privacy. This privacy policy begins applying to visitors and customers as soon as they visit A Small Orange's website for the first time.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, A Small Orange collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. A Small Orange's purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how A Small Orange's visitors use its website. From time to time, A Small Orange may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate. e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to A Small Orange's website choose to interact with A Small Orange in ways that require A Small Orange to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that A Small Orange gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who choose to signup for our newsletter for their name and email address. Those who engage in transactions with A Small Orange, usually by purchasing web hosting services or registering a domain name, for example, are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, A Small Orange collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor's interaction with A Small Orange. A Small Orange does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities, including from becoming a customer of A Small Orange.

In some cases, A Small Orange will ask website visitors wishing to become customers of A Small Orange to provide additional information beyond what was requested in the signup form. This information is requested to verify the customer's identity and to reduce the likelihood of fraud, which is common in the web hosting industry in which A Small Orange operates. Customers not wishing to provide such information as requested may not be permitted to become customers of A Small Orange.

### Aggregated Statistics

A Small Orange may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites and its customers. For instance, A Small Orange may publish the number of s sent per month or the total number of installations of a certain software package. A Small Orange may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, A Small Orange does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

A Small Orange discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on A Small Orange's behalf or to provide services available to A Small Orange's customers, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using A Small Orange's products and services, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. A Small Orange will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, A Small Orange discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request.

If you are a customer of A Small Orange and have supplied your email address, A Small Orange may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new products or services, solicit your feedback, inform you of an outage or interruption in service, or just keep you up to date with what's going on with A Small Orange and our products and services. We primarily use our blog, forums, Twitter account, and similar presences to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or through our billing system), we reserve the right to publish it (with personally identifiable information removed as necessary) in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other customers.A Small Orange takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. A Small Orange uses cookies to help A Small Orange identify and track visitors, their usage of A Small Orange's website, and their website access preferences. A Small Orange visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using A Small Orange's website or using its products or services, with the drawback that certain features of A Small Orange's websites, products, and services may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, A Small Orange may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, with or without notice, and in A Small Orange's sole discretion. A Small Orange will post changes to its Privacy Policy directly on this page and encourages visitors to regularly check this page for any changes to this Privacy Policy. Your continued use of A Small Orange's products and services after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
